MARK VITAL

Full Stack Web Developer

PROFILE

I'm a full stack developer leaning towards front-end with an eye for user interfaces and a sense of usability and hands-on experience building products from scratch.

I have worked in large corporations for half of my career and in a startups later on. I feel like I have now combined both the professionalism of working on advanced products with the hacker mindset of a startup. I lean towards using open-sources frameworks, tools to achieve fast results balancing with software best practices.

SKILLS

- Front end: React.js, ES6 Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS (modules, styled c.), SVG, MUI
- Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Jest, Laravel (I've come to appreciate the MERN stack more lately), Jekyll, Java, PHP, static state generators (Gatsby.js, Next.js), AWS, Docker, Nginx, GraphQL, REST, TypeORM, Type-DI, Postgres
- Web3: solid understanding of core Web3 concepts like cryptocurrency, tokens, smart contracts, NFT, DAO, wallets, IPFS, ethers.js
- Design: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, Figma, UI sketching and prototyping, infographics
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Webpack, ESLint, Chrome DevTools, GitHub, Docker, npm, Cypress, Postman, LLMs, Tableau, SpreadSheets
- Best Practices: CI/CD, version control (git), TDD, DRY, KISS, Agile, Kanban
- Leadership: comfortable leading small teams, mentorship, compassionate coding

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER, UNSTOPPABLE DOMAINS, - MAY - NOV 2022 Worked on user profiles pages that link to their NFT domain names and user-uploaded NFTs. Improved domain search features. Worked on domain management that interacted with smart contracts and NFT cache.

Tech: React.js, Node.js, TypeScript, Next.js, Material UI, Google Cloud, Moralis Web3 API, OpenSea API, ethers.js

LEAD DEVELOPER / CTO, ADIOMA PTE.LTD. - 2016-2022

Building from scratch a web-based graphics editor for generating information graphics. Launched as a SAAS, got to 100,000 users /3,000 paying customers.

I was leading a team of developers, doing coding, product design, testing and support.

Tech: React.js, PHT, Laravel, REST, MySQL, FastSpring, Elastic Search, NGinx, OVH Cloud

DEVELOPER / DATA VISUALIZATION, FNF LABS - 2012-2016

I held the position of information designer and developer at a compact Data Visualization agency, overseeing all technical aspects of the company's operations.

Created data visualizations and infographics using D3.js, Javascript, SVG, Python for companies such as Google, Cisco, Thermofisher Scientific, World Bank, and many others.

Tech: D3.js, React.js, SVG, CSS animation, Tableu, Open Refine, FreeBase, AWS, Wordpress

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GOOGLE - 2010-2011

Contributed to a web-based tool that tests HTML features across different browsers. I maintained the test runner written in Java and wrote new tests in Javascript.

Tech: Java, Python, JavaScript, HTML, various internal Google framework and tools

SENIOR JAVA DEVELOPER, WEBMD - 2009-2010

Integrated a drug interaction API with the existing application that catalogs drugs. Using Java and Javascript, I built a tool that allowed our users (doctors) to look up multiple drugs and explore the results of their interaction.

Tech: Java, Spring Framework, Hibernate ORM, MySQL, Nginx, Linux

EDUCATION

KYIV POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY - B.S. AND M.S. IN APPLIED MATH (2008)

HOBBIES

SWIMMING, HIKING, PLAYING GO, SCI-FI MOVIES, INFOGRAPHICS

PORTFOLIO

HTTPS://MARKVITAL.GITHUB.IO

